Contact

alin.m.nica@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/alinnica (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership
Management
Software Architecture

Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
French (Elementary)
German (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Romanian (Native or Bilingual)

Alin Nica

Dedicated to building practical and effective tech teams developing products for humans.

Berlin Metropolitan Area

Summary

Committed Tech Manager with experience in payments, social networks and e-commerce. Leading cross-functional teams to achieve the goals of the business, while also facilitating individuals reach their professional goals. Most comfortable on the server side, writing go code, managing infrastructure with docker, kubernetes, AWS.

Experience

Spark Networks

7 years

Director Of Technology May 2021 - April 2024 (3 years)

Berlin, Germany

Responsible for all technical aspects of zoosk.com, a broad market dating platform. Guiding cross-functional development teams and implementing DevOps to deliver new features to our users, while maintaining, cost-optimising and improving the existing technical stack. PHP/Java/Go/Typescript on kubernetes and AWS infrastructure.

Head of Platform Integrations May 2017 - May 2021 (4 years 1 month)

Berlin Area, Germany

Managing a medium size remote team focused on the development and maintenance of the platform Zoosk. Heavily involved in payments and fraud topics.

Previously engaged in integrating new platforms (M&A) into the company infrastructure and policies. Fully supporting and maintaining newly purchased platforms using php, go, node.js, react, kubernetes, aws.

Supporting monitoring and on-call rotation.

Involved in product planning and strategy, guiding personal growth for team members, mentoring and expanding technical knowledge.

Managing workflow and controls (incl. SOX compliance) and support capitalisation reports.

Experienced in personnel management, hiring.

Lendico

Lead Software Engineer
January 2014 - May 2017 (3 years 5 months)

Berlin Area, Germany

Worked in a medium-sized team to build Lendico from scratch with Symfony2(php)

Subsequently managed a part of the team to focus on specific aspects of the software (mostly growth)

Was introduced to the go language and started developing software using it. Involved in building critical systems like accounting, investor reporting using Symfony2(php) and go. Personal focus lied with architecture, TDD/BDD, CI/CD.

Was introduced to kubernetes, running on bare metal, and started improving my devops skills.

Rocket Internet GmbH
Senior Software Engineer
February 2012 - January 2014 (2 years)
Berlin Area, Germany

Developing web shop applications with PHP(Zend, Symfony2) and Javascript. Bootstrapping startups.

Involved in different projects:

- Zalora
- Warehousing/Order managment system
- Hellofresh

Agora Internet GmbH
Front End Web Developer
June 2011 - February 2012 (9 months)
Berlin Area, Germany

Working on the frontend of the lucrato drugstore cart comparison site.

webabout freelance web developer February 2008 - September 2011 (3 years 8 months) Presentation websites for different one-time customers. Some hosting and maintenance.

Wixi.com web developer October 2010 - June 2011 (9 months)

Radio UBB
Moderator and Editor
January 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 6 months)

Radio Charivari Intern October 2009 - December 2009 (3 months)

AIESEC

Communication Teamleader - Corporate Sector 2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Education

Babes-Bolyai University Journalism · (2007 - 2010)

Babes-Bolyai University Physics · (2006 - 2008)